Dr. Khalifa: أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
[30:25] ... the heaven and the earth are standing at His disposal. Finally, He calls you out of the earth, one call, whereupon you immediately rise.
[30:26] To Him belongs everyone in the heaven and the earth; all are subservient to Him.
[30:27] And He is the One who initiates the creation, then repeats it; this is the easiest thing for Him. And to Him belongs the most sublime similitude, in the heavens and the earth, and He is the Almighty, Most Wise.
Absurdity of Idolatry
[30:28] He cites for you herein an example from among yourselves: Do you ever elevate your servants or subordinates to the level where they rival you, and to the point that you pay them as much allegiance as is being paid to you? We thus explain the revelations for the people who understand.
[30:29] Indeed, the transgressors have followed their own opinions, without knowledge. Thus, who can guide those who have been sent astray by GOD? No one can ever help them.
Monotheism is Natural Instinct*
[30:30] Therefore, you shall devote yourself to the religion of strict monotheism. Such is the natural instinct placed into the people by GOD. Such creation of GOD will never change. This is the perfect religion, but most people do not know.
[30:31] You shall submit to Him, reverence Him, observe the Contact Prayers (Salat), and do not be among the idol worshipers.
[30:32] Do not be among those who divide their religion into sects; each party rejoicing with what they have.
The footnote 30:30 says, Recognizing God ALONE as our Lord and Master is a natural instinct. We are born into this world with such an instinct. As shown in 7:172 and Appendix 7.
How do you like that?
Just every page of the Quran says, God alone, God alone, God alone.
So, there is no excuse for, for going any other way.
It's amazing how much, how hard they work to go to Hell.
I mean, they try every trick in the book to associate others with God.
And will... they're just tricks.
Well, just there is endless number of tricks to have them associate Muhammad or Hussein or Jesus with God.
But here, the first verse is
[30:25] Among His signs is that the heavens and the earth are standing at His disposal. Finally, He calls you out of the earth, one call, whereupon you immediately rise.
When we rise on that Day, we're going to know everything.
We will go our initial blasphemy. We will know that we went, we were sent to the earth for more schooling, to learn that the...
we were back into God's kingdom.
And we'll know that only He is King, that only He is capable of being a god.
When Satan thought that he can be a god besides God, it was not just arrogance or pride.
He simply was wrong.
It was not, it was not possible.
And this demonstration that we're having today proves that.
[30:26] To Him belongs everyone in the heavens and the earth; ...
We belong to Him.
[30:26] ... all are subservient to Him.
God created us. We are God's creatures.
He owns us.
And we are indeed fortunate that He is Arrahman Arraheem, the Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
Because we are His creatures.
When the other creatures said "send them all to Hell", God said "no, I'll give them another chance."
And this is the, this is the ultimate love.
And here are creatures who are blaspheming against Him.
And God said "I will send them back to be redeemed.
And actually, God is accepting the flimsiest excuses to redeem us.
Gives us 40 years.
Look how many millions of people are going to the Lower Heaven instead of Hell,
going to Heaven instead of Hell.
How many millions who would have gone to Hell because of the initial crime.
Dr. Khalifa: But they're going to Heaven, instead. This is God's Mercy. Ismail Barakat: All those kids who are starving.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Not only that. Look at, I used Martin Luther King and Malcolm X,
people who almost made it to 40.
But they are saved and sent to Heaven, instead.
Had they lived, they would have been swept into the Christianity wave.
Ismail Barakat: The question that arose not too long ago in Vancouver is "if God is so Merciful, why does He let children starve in Africa, for example?"
Ismail Barakat: In fact, if you look at the situation very carefully, you will find that they are dying out of His Mercy.
Because they're guaranteed.
Ismail Barakat: I would trade places with these kids any time.
Dr. Khalifa: This only... Not only that, but it's Satan's incompetence. They are victims of Satan.
Because whoever asked the question will not be satisfied. "They're still suffering. They're still hungry."
"They're still... Why suffer for one second?", for example.
Dr. Khalifa: But it is a demonstration of Satan's incompetence.
Ismail Barakat: And Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala stepped in and corrected for Satan's incompetence by putting these kids in Paradise.
Dr. Khalifa: What God does, He assigns.
"Why did he have to go through that?"
Dr. Khalifa: "If God is Merciful, why did he have..." Ismail Barakat: Demonstration of...
A woman: Their children would (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Ismail Barakat: It is a demonstration of Satan's incompetence.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, that's a very important point.
A man: So, Satan doesn't really want us to go to Heaven.
Dr. Khalifa: To Heaven?
Dr. Khalifa: No. A man: Because he (unintelligible),
A man: he wants us to join him in Hell. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A man: So, actually...
Dr. Khalifa: Actually, what Satan is doing now, we have to look at the total picture.
What Satan wants to do now is prove that he was right,
that he can have a perfect world, or a perfect dominion.
Because he knows that the matter of Heaven and Hell is already decided. He knows that.
But what he wants to prove is that he wants to tell God "I'm right."
"I was right when I thought... I have enough qualifications and enough power to run a dominion, and I didn't goof off."
But things get out of hand as the number of people increases.
For example, why do we have AIDS now? Where was it 100 years ago?
Where did it come from, AIDS?
And you can see that the world is getting more... there's more progress, there is more convenience.
We're sitting in air conditioning and fans.
We... There is cars and planes and comfort.
Different kinds of luxuries.
Ok. So, he's been working to please the...
He's really working to make the human beings enjoy and have a perfect health, perfect wealth,
perfect systems, economic systems, and so on. He's been doing this.
Dr. Khalifa: But the population is increasing, the human beings, and things are getting out of hand.
A man: Rashad, ...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, beyond his capacity.
And there are experiments that are going on to prove that he's not omnipotent or omniscient, for example.
And this, the miracle of the Quran is a perfect example.
I worked... This miracle came out, some of you may be shocked who didn't hear it before,
but this miracle came out of the biggest brewery in the whole world, the biggest alcohol manufacturing place in the whole world.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you know that? Did you know that? A man: This miracle?
Dr. Khalifa: This miracle of the Quran.
A man: Because you were working there. Yes, I know.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Ismail Barakat: Anheuser-Busch
A man: But I thought you were working for Monsanto.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, I was working for Monsanto enough to learn the computer programming
and to use the computers, computerize the chemical research.
And then, I took the data, all the papers, and I moved on to Anheuser-Busch.
I was giving a paper in Chicago. There was an American Chemical Society meeting in Chicago.
Dr. Khalifa: And I was giving a paper, and after I finished, there comes this man and he says "I'm Bob Seeley. I'm Director of Research at Anheuser-Busch."
A man: Seeley? Dr. Khalifa: Yes, Bob Seeley.
A man: S-E-E-L-A-Y. Dr. Khalifa: S-E-E-L-E-Y.
Dr. Khalifa: "I'm Bob Seeley, Director of Research at Anheuser-Busch, and I would like you to come and work with us."
I said "sorry, there's no way." You know, I laughed.
And he said "why?"
I said "I'm a Muslim, and we don't believe in alcohol, and I don't think I'll wanna have anything to do with it.
He said "this has nothing to do with alcohol."
I said "well, still, but the name Anheuser-Busch, I don't want my name on a card with Anheuser-Busch in the same card."
He said "you're gonna be in the food research division. You're a protein biochemist."
"And we want to get protein out of millions of tons of brewer's yeast that we throw away, and baker's yeast."
They also make baker's yeast.
"We're throwing these millions of tons of protein. As you know, yeast has 50% protein."
"50% protein", which is true.
And we would like to recover all this protein and process it into artificial eggs, meat, whatever."
Dr. Khalifa: It's protein. Protein is protein is protein, meat, eggs, beans.
Ismail Barakat: It's all the same stuff. Dr. Khalifa: "It's all protein, same stuff, and we're throwing it down the drain."
I said "sorry, there's no way I'll do that."
And he said "are you afraid of the people or afraid of God?" You know, he's getting into this kind of thing.
And I said "I'm happy. I'm happy at Monsanto. I don't want, I don't want to change."
He said "how much are you making at Monsanto?
I said, "$14,000." That was a lot of money, then.
He said "we'll give you $22,000."
I said "where do I sign?"
It's been all this long arguing, you could have told me first.
Huh?
Really, what?
Yes.
Yes. Then, I went. I moved. It's the same town.
Dr. Khalifa: Except, I had to drive on the freeway for 20 more minutes.
Ismail Barakat: For seventh time, how (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, I moved on to Anheuser-Busch.
And I tell you, today, they have a whole building called Research and Development, huge building, beautiful laboratories and so on.
But when I was hired there, which they were telling me, he told me "we're gonna have a new research building."
But I never, never got to that.
But so, my office was in the brewery, the biggest brewery in the world, which is making alcohol.
And so, I took all this data into my office.
And to go further, show you how miraculous it is, one of the biggest problems with yeast was to break the cell wall to get the protein out.
So, this is the cell wall. You have to break it to get the protein out.
And that was a problem for 150 years since they started research on the yeast, to get the protein out.
But right now, I have a patented process, for the benefit of Anheuser-Busch, of breaking the wall and getting the protein out.
Ismail Barakat: You developed it?
Dr. Khalifa: I developed it and I patented it.
A man: Isn't it so that the fact that what, you were doing, you were actually trying to perfect the system of Satan.
Dr. Khalifa: No, I didn't. A man: Because... But may I
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, God ahead. A man: ...finish my line of thoughts?
A man: Because you didn't want to work with alcohol.
And then he said "But you will take the product that comes out of alcohol production and use it for the benefit of mankind."
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Exactly. This is actually, this is one line that he told me. A man: What I'm trying to say...
A man: ... is that the system of Satan is incompetent.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: And that was a by-product.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. A man: But imagine if you had used all this yeast and proteins
A man: without making any alcohol at all, but using it all for proteins.
A man: But you were doing, you were actually supporting the manufacture of alcohol by upgrading using yeast. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, I see your point. I see what you mean.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, Seeley showed me, actually showed me an article, a United Nations report, that there will be famine in Egypt by 1975.
Dr. Khalifa: And he said "don't you want to be an active participant in eliminating famine?" This was one of the lines. Ismail Barakat: Egypt, no.
So, I took all this data. Now, the reason I'm mentioning, breaking the cell wall
is that the process was to put the yeast, mix it with potassium hydroxide,
and for four hours, have it heating for four hours.
This is how you break that. So, what do I do for four hours?
So, I go in the morning, take the yeast, put it in a big beaker, put sodium hydroxide and let it cook for four hours. What do I do now?
Isamail Barakat: Read books.
Dr. Khalifa: So first of all, this made them very happy. It was a breakthrough.
Second of all, it gave me four hours, you know, from 8 to noon, in order to look at the data and analyze it and confirm the counts of the letters.
And I was working on the miracle for four years.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the whole miracle came out of Anheuser-Busch. Ismail Barakat: Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala
Dr. Khalifa: Now the point, the point before I forget, is that if we pray, if we play, this is something we used to do,
play a game where we hide a little ball, for example.
Play a game. One of us will go and hide it in a place, and we'll go looking for it, and when it gets hot, we'll clap faster or slower.
It's a game like that.
Dr. Khalifa: And one of us will get out and look, and we'll all clap, it's hot or cool. You know that game?
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the best way to hide the ball will be in the person's pocket.
A man: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: It's the last thing he will look at. So, God hid the miracle in Satan's pocket.
And this is how it came out. Because why was it 1400 years?
Satan will do his utmost, as you know, to hide this.
Not to let the world know.
You understand the point? So, Satan is not omniscient, is he?
Because Satan, looking at the planet Earth, and he wants to find the people to mislead.
He says "Aha, there's Masjid Tucson, I better go and mislead those people."
But, I mean, he sees the brewery and says "oh no, those are mine. They're in my pocket. Let me find another place."
Ismail Barakat: "These are my guys." Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: But, you know Rashad, when Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala created the yeast cell, He created it for this discovery. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, for that design.
Why didn't anybody think of potassium hydroxide? They used sodium hydroxide hydrolysis.
I think they concluded from that that potassium hydroxide do not work.
Because sodium and potassium are very similar.
Dr. Khalifa: They tried acids, all kinds of acids, and they didn't work. But potassium hydroxide worked.
A woman: Why did you think of that? Dr. Khalifa: I don't know.
Ismail Barakat: Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala.
Dr. Khalifa: I think I read all the literature and I found that they used all these, but not potassium hydroxide. I said "hmm, let me try it."
Sure enough, the cell was broken and the protein came out.
Feroz: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
Feroz: Does potassium hydroxide have an atomic weight or...?
Dr. Khalifa: Molecular Ismail Barakat: Yes, of course.
Feroz: What is it?
Dr. Khalifa: I don't know. I have to look up the table.
A woman:What is the chemical...
Dr. Khalifa: 57 is iron, 56 is iron but one of the isomers is 57, and Sura 57 is "Iron." There's a whole book on that.
Ismail Barakat: What is Sura? What is...
Dr. Khalifa: So, Satan's omniscience is eliminated because of this. This is... Because this is the biggest defeat for Satan.
This mathematical miracle of the Quran is something that he worked very hard to prevent,
Dr. Khalifa: but it came out of his pocket.
Ismail Barakat: But he wasn't even aware of it.
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm? Ismail Barakat: He didn't know it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, he did. A woman: Sure he did.
Dr. Khalifa: He did. A woman: Sure. Because he tried to (unintelligible) Ismail Barakat: He did, hmm?
Dr. Khalifa: It's Bahaism. A woman: The Bahais
Dr. Khalifa: He established Bahaism. Yeah. Ismail Barakat: Ah, yeah, yeah.
He, he... I mean, it's easy for him to know that. It's very easy for him to know that.
Satan probably knew... In that other dimension, Satan probably knows that all God's creation has the 19 on it.
And then, he reads in the Quran, [74:30] On it are nineteen.
So, I mean, he's not stupid, by no means.
Dr. Khalifa: He's very stupid, I'm sorry, but I mean, the relative.
A man: He's sly. He's sly.
Dr. Khalifa: He's very stupid for thinking that he can be a god. A man: He's sly on (unintelligible) A woman: He's not intelligent but he has a lot of knowledge.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: His knowledge (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Of course, of course. I mean, he's just overestimating his powers. And...
God did not give him... Actually, God is giving him another chance to prove that.
Dr. Khalifa: But he knows better than making such a claim.
A man: So, the fact that, for...
Dr. Khalifa: There are many, many, many millions of creatures like Satan in God's kingdom. But he's the only one who went off.
A man: The fact that 20,000 children are dying every day in the world of starvation, actually makes Satan really annoyed.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Because it proves every day that he's really incompetent. Dr. Khalifa: Because he's incompetent.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly, exactly. But again, back to God's Mercy, to give us 40 years, is really giving us the flimsiest excuses to save us, redeem us, take us to Heaven.
The people who live beyond 40 and then fight God had to be very bad as far as that blasphemy was concerned.
So, if any of us had an atom of leaning towards God during that big feud, God apparently is saving all those people.
Dr. Khalifa: And there are millions, and we'll be so thankful in the Hereafter.
A woman: Mã Shã Allãh. Excuse me, what would be Sheytan's punishment?
Dr. Khalifa: Exile from God's kingdom.
Dr. Khalifa: Hell.
A woman: I mean, but he's made of fire himself. So, I mean, Hell wouldn't hurt him.
Dr. Khalifa: Hell is not fire.
A woman: Not fire.
Dr. Khalifa: See, remember Hell and Heaven are allegories.
Ismail Barakat: Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala...
Dr. Khalifa: Who?
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: It's 1:30. The plane leaves at what time?
A man: 2:30. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You have one hour.
Dr. Khalifa: See, another good surprise. Where's Parivash?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Let's listen to Feroz's question.
Dr. Khalifa: What did you say?
Feroz: Isn't there a verse in the Quran that says that the devils are forbidden from understanding Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: On this dimension. In this dimension.
Feroz: What about the jinns? They don't know. Because they heard Moses... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: (72:1) سَمِعْنَا قُرْءَانًا عَجَبًۭا Feroz: They don't know the Quran, right? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: (72:2) يَهْدِىٓ إِلَى ٱلرُّشْدِ Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Feroz: But Satan does?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, Oh, this is exactly the example I was looking for.
Dr. Khalifa: We were talking this morning, is it the same people, we were talking about how, when the prophet Muhammad said
"Say, I'm afraid if I disobey my Lord, I'm afraid of a terrible retribution."
Ismail Barakat: "The retribution on a terrible day." Dr. Khalifa: How many people did we discuss this with?
Dr. Khalifa: And I was looking for an example where Qul (قل) "say" means it is done.
So, the verse is saying [72:1] Say, "I was inspired that a number of jinns listened to ... the Quran.
And they went to their people.
Dr. Khalifa: So, this is something I was involved in. Ismail Barakat: (72:1) قُلْ أُوحِىَ إِلَىَّ أَنَّهُ
Dr. Khalifa: This is a good example. It was already done. I didn't need... It says,
قُلْ أُوحِىَ إِلَىَّ
"Say, I was inspired to say that a number of jinns listened to the Quran, and this was already happened, done.
So, I was saying that when the prophet Muhammad was ordered to say "I'm afraid if I disobey my Lord"
Oh, Muhammad, it was you.
Remember you asked the question if Muhammad's property belonged to the state or to his children, and there was fight,
and I told you, you will not find anything that Muhammad took for himself.
And I was positive about that because of that verse.
Dr. Khalifa: He will see to it that nothing entered his pocket that was not belonging to him, that belonged to the state or...
Ismail Barakat: That he was not entitled to.
Dr. Khalifa: Right, exactly.
Because Muhammad was telling me a Hadith and Sunnah story that after the prophet died, they were fighting over who inherits his property. Is it the state or his children?
Ismail Barakat: Not all of his property, Rashad. It was only certain property.
Dr. Khalifa: No, none of it. None of it. He did not have any property that was not his.
Ismail Barakat: But the fight was specifically over that... Dr. Khalifa: There was no fight.
Dr. Khalifa: See, we have, we must learn not to take off on a Hadith story or something.
You cannot make an assumption. Somebody says this is red.
And then, you go on discussing why it is red because the assumption itself is wrong.
Dr. Khalifa: Muhammad.
Muhammad: Yeah. You said "Hell is not fire." What is Hell?
Dr. Khalifa: Hell is exile from God and not having...
Dr. Khalifa: First of all, we have no way of comprehending how, what Heaven is and what Hell is.
A man: Hell is hate and Heaven is love.
Dr. Khalifa: Hell is exile from God. It's exile that is farther from this earth.
Dr. Khalifa: Wake up. You mustn't sleep.
Ismail Barakat: No, I'm listening to what you're saying. You're saying that Hell is exile from God. Dr. Khalifa: I want you to understand...
Dr. Khalifa: I want you to understand this very... Look. Listen to this carefully.
Dr. Khalifa: We are here in the seventh universe, in the heart of the seventh universe.
And you can see how many problems the people have. Alcoholism, accidents, divorce, miseries.
There will be an eighth universe on the Day of Judgment. The eighth universe will be Hell.
Can you imagine how far it will be?
This is why God says "we're gonna fold the heavens and the earth like the folding of a book."
And then in Sura 14, God says "I will create new heavens and new earth."
And this time there will be eight of them, not seven.
They'll probably be much bigger.
And the eighth universe will be much farther from God. So that's Hell.
It will be much worse.
We have no way of comprehending how bad it is.
See, even, now in this seventh universe, God is taking care of all the provisions, providing for all the ants and the horses and the people.
But in the eighth universe there is no such thing.
The people will be in the new form of butterflies instead of caterpillars.
There'll be different kinds of...
Dr. Khalifa: And they will try to come to the seventh universe.
Parivash: That means that the people who are going to Hell, instead of going up, they're falling down.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, yes, farther, yes. Yes, exactly, exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A woman: So, Rashad, what's the meaning when in the Quran says that you will be the ones who are
in Hell, you will be burned and then re-burn again and then re-burn again?
Ismail Barakat: There is no death.
A woman: What does that mean?
Dr. Khalifa: It's all allegorical.
All the descriptions of Hell and Heaven in the Quran are allegorical, all of them.
But you get glimpses of what it is like, like in Sura 57, when the hypocrites come and try to beg for light.
This means energy.
Dr. Khalifa: Go take a nap. Come on, go.
Feroz: It should be more like, It will be more like in a sense, like angels that travel from the high universes that travel all the way down here.
Feroz: And the Quran says that the believers will go down and meet people. Dr. Khalifa: We'll go visit
Dr. Khalifa: our friends and relatives in Hell.
Ismail Barakat: That is most people you know.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. It's gonna be fantastic.
That, that day of, this Eternal Day of the real life is going to be fantastic. Because it's everything...
You're walking around now as a king or queen on earth, but nobody knows you,
which is wonderful, because you don't need secret service guards.
Dr. Khalifa: We go to the subway in Washington, D.C., walking among the people.
There are actually guards around you.
Sometimes it happens literally, like with Ihsan.
She was going to Africa, Sierra Leone.
I told her they will, so that you're (اميرة الامراء), you know, a servant of God and a princess, and they will meet you
with red carpets and 21-gun salute and the lines of soldiers and so on.
And soon enough she went to Africa and landed, and there's the red carpet and 21-gun salute and the soldiers and lines.
And they thought they were meeting the president of Gambia, you know, who was on the same plane with her.
Ihsan: (Unintelligible) They were traveling with me.
Ihsan: (Unintelligible) traveling with us.
(unintelligible) another day.
So, he said (unintelligible)
There is a private secret service.
Ihsan: (unintelligible) and the 21-gun salutes will do it. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: She told... Oh, you told her your granddaughter is a college student?
Ihsan: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: She's a college student.
Dr. Khalifa: And she probably thought that, I'm just thinking highly of you.
Ihsan: Yes, and I tell her how nice you are, how high you think of me, how you describe this.
Ihsan: And after a while, from London, here comes a lot of people, promotions, (unintelligible) checking everybody sitting behind a chair and said,
Ihsan: and then said "what's happening?" I said "The VIP and the..."
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Ihsan: "VIP", just like this. She said "VIP." They will not say who or...
Dr. Khalifa: We know. Ihsan: We know.
Ihsan: But then, they have a carpet. The red carpet was there, and the music, and the 21-gun salute, and the leader of Gambia was traveling with us.
Dr. Khalifa: But she didn't say what Sunayta said.
So, they are landing, imagine her granddaughter, they're landing, and there's the red carpet,
and the 21-gun salute, and things that we said.
She said "Grandma, Grandma, they are doing it."
Isamil Barakat: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Rashad was right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: This is what you said?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, Muhammad.
Muhammad: Yes. Rashad, Sura 101, it says here in Arabic,
(101:8) وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَفَّتْ مَوَٰزِينُهُۥ (101:9) فَأُمُّهُۥ هَاوِيَةٌۭ (101:10) وَمَآ أَدْرَىٰكَ مَا هِيَهْ
Dr. Khalifa: Muhammad: (101:11) نَارٌ حَامِيَةٌۢ
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Muhammad: That Narun (نَارٌ) and Jahim (جَحِيمَ) Dr. Khalifa: Yes, yes.
Muhammad: And in Sura 102 (102:6) لَتَرَوُنَّ ٱلْجَحِيمَ
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Muhammad: which is translated here to [102:6] You would envision Hell.
Muhammad: And this [101:11] The blazing Hellfire.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's all allegorical, all of it.
You see, the first, yeah, the first... At the very beginning of the Quran, when God talked about Heaven and Hell, He told us this is allegorical.
Yes, they're all allegorical. There's no, it's not fire. It's mostly darkness, actually.
Dr. Khalifa: Mostly darkness. Remember, "we need some of your light."
Feroz: Spiritual darkness or actual physical darkness?
Dr. Khalifa: Both.
A man: Both (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Because the eighth universe, God will not give them stars or anything.
Parivash: Yes, and it's just a proof that if Sheytan is from fire, and Hell is fire, it doesn't hurt him. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah,
Dr. Khalifa: he'd enjoy it. No, it'd be a little provision.
No, it's not fire at all, and Heaven is not trees and spouses and food, fruit.
Dr. Khalifa: It's indescribably fantastic.
Feroz: Maybe, Hell will be very cold because so far, no stars, and Sheytan, you know, Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Feroz: made of fire in the cold where is...
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Here we go.
Dr. Khalifa: You see, we understand a lot from, from the, understand, we have quite a bit of information, you know, in the Quran.
When we learn that we can go and visit our relatives and friends, and they will be coming around us like butterflies go around the light.
Imagine a thousand acres of Alfalfa, what is that? Clover? I was gonna say clover.
Alfalfa, for example.
There's millions of butterflies, and it's pitch dark in that one thousand acres, and then you send the light.
Huh?
Right.
So, we will go there, and we're gonna visit, and they will come and they will beg for light.
Dr. Khalifa: And we'll go and meet them, and we will talk to them, and we'll say "thank God that I didn't listen to you."
Feroz: Will we have any remorse? Dr. Khalifa: It's Sura 37. Never. No.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. This is another point. "Will we have any remorse? Will you feel sorry for them?"
A woman: What is "remorse"? A woman: Sadness. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Sadness. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: We will not feel sorry for them. There'll be no sorrow at all.
Feroz: Even if they're good friends or relatives or whatever?
Dr. Khalifa: Even if they are the best of friends, because you realize they well deserved what they wanted, and that they insisted on going there.
I loved my father very much. He loved me very much all our lives.
Dr. Khalifa: But I don't feel sorry for him, because he was fighting God actively, and he insisted on going to Hell.
A man: He wanted it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, he wanted it bad. I mean,
Because I talked to him here for four months in this masjid.
And the last, one of the times, he stood out here, outside the mosque.
"I'm not going in this masjid unless you add Muhammad to the Azan (Call to Prayer).
Yes.
I said "then, you cannot come in here because the idol worshippers are filth."
Dr. Khalifa: I had to use that expression from the Quran. Ismail Barakat: Subhan Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: I said "this is idol worship. You're not satisfied with God alone. So..."
I'm giving you an example of my own father, because I really loved him immensely.
And I was his favorite for a long time until I said "God alone."
Ismail Barakat: (9:28) إِنَّمَا ٱلْمُشْرِكُونَ نَجَسٌۭ
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, I mean, he went to extremes.
He went from loving me excessively to calling someone to have me put away, prisoned or killed.
Then, he died 19 days later.
So, we will not feel sorry for them because they insisted on it. This is what they wanted.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, you will.
A woman: What?
Dr. Khalifa: Ihsan.
Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, (101:9) فَأُمُّهُۥ هَاوِيَةٌۭ
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, going down.
Dr. Khalifa: ...is down. Going down.
Dr. Khalifa: Muhammad, did you hear this?
Muhammad: Excuse me.
Dr. Khalifa: Did you hear what...
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Parivash was saying that this means when the new universe is set up, the people heading for Hell will go down to the 8th universe.
And then, right after that, you read the verse, (101:9) فَأُمُّهُۥ هَاوِيَةٌۭ
Faumuhu (فَأُمُّهُۥ), you know, is "ahead of him is" or whatever, "his destiny is going down."
HAWA means somebody who falls, like if somebody falls from a plane or a rock falls from a plane, this is HAWA, it goes down.
Ismail Barakat: Hawiya (هَاوِيَةٌۭ) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa (Speaking Arabic): (Unintelligible)
Ihsan: (101:8) وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَفَّتْ مَوَٰزِينُهُۥ (101:9) فَأُمُّهُۥ هَاوِيَةٌ
Ismail Barakat: Meaning "No support."
Ihsan: (101:10) وَمَآ أَدْرَىٰكَ مَا هِيَهْ (101:11) نَارٌ حَامِيَةٌۢ
Dr. Khalifa: Shading smile is there.
A man: It's more about the...
Ismail Barakat: It means, it means lack of support, Rashad.
Ismail Barakat: Hawiya (هَاوِيَةٌ)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, YAHWI means... well, no. Ismail Barakat: To fall down, huh?
Muhammad: How about TASLANAR ALHAMIYA?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Muhammad (Speaking Arabic): (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: I understand, Muhammad, that it is described as fire in here.
Dr. Khalifa: And Heaven is described as a garden, but we are told this is allegorical.
Ismail Barakat: It's not to be allegorical because had he been addressing Eskimos, he would have spoken of frozen place.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
I want to give you an example.
A woman: Because our consciousness cannot grasp it.
A woman: (unintelligible) A man: Yes.
Parivash: Yeah, we have some expression in Farsi.
Parivash (Speaking Farsi): When you say my heart burnt and was set on fire. A woman: I just said that.
A woman: But in English, when you say you burned my heart, it means you burn my...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, doesn't mean fire. A woman: doesn't mean it is fire. Parivash: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible) Exactly.
A man: (unintelligible) somewhere as quiet. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: No matter how you (unintelligible)
Ismail Barakat: Also, Muhammad, he describes Paradise as a place with flowing rivers and cool breezes. You see, obviously, it's not.
Ismail Barakat: It's much more than that.
Dr. Khalifa: Rivers of milk, honey, and wine.
A woman: The hotels in Hawaii that look like Paradise. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: But doesn't Hawaii look like Paradise? It's a good describing. But obviously, it's not. A woman: Hawaii...
A woman: ...and believers go there. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Obviously, important. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. ‘Alaykum Al-Salãm.
A woman: See, I remember an appendix in the Gold Quran that says that our minds are not able to comprehend except by the level of our consciousness. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
A woman: So, it gives us a picture that we can use to comprehend. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: And this Sura being "Romans", and now I understand I want to read it. And in the Bible, Romans, In chapter 1, verse 21, I think it is.
A woman: It's verse that says "that man
Dr. Khalifa: "What an eye never saw"
A woman: Well, it says that mankind has this condition whereby he cannot accept God unless he puts to Him some kind of imagery, some kind of form.
A woman: And now, this is telling us about the idolization. So, whether it's by idolatry or even for the believers to come to non-idolatry, we have to have some picture. But it seems correlational...
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Nora, Nora, go back to the...
A woman: (unintelligible) whether they're making a statute (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, I've been trying to avoid saying this, but I'd say this since we're all adults anyway.
Dr. Khalifa: It's like a child. You just try to describe sexual orgasm to a child.
Ismail Barakat: There are no words, honestly.
Dr. Khalifa: How will you describe it?
It's something that they will grow and it's ahead of them,
Dr. Khalifa: 20 years from now. So, this is 6- or 7-year old.
Ismail Barakat: There's no way you can understand it. Dr. Khalifa: Right. Right.
A man: But, in the socialist totalitarian dictatorship, they are teaching the children in the school.
Ismail Barakat: Yes, but they still... A man: They are trying (unintelligible) 60 years old.
Ismail Barakat: There's no way you can understand it. You cannot...
Dr. Khalifa: How will they describe it?
A man: But then, they... Dr. Khalifa: How?
Dr. Khalifa: How do you describe to a child who never experienced it?
A man: I will tell you... A woman: (unintelligible)
A man: I will tell you... A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right. Exactly.
A woman: Right. Right.
A man: Listen, I will tell you a horror story.
A man: Rashad, with your permission
Dr. Khalifa: Now, we know how good Tom is. A man: I will tell you...
A man: I will tell you a true fact.
A man: You know what they do in Sweden?
A man: In Sweden, there is a law.
It says, compulsory day care for children from 18 months.
So, all the children are more or less forcibly put in the day care center for the age of 18 months.
There are two books that the day care personnel are supposed to use.
Not all of them are using it because they understand that they are satanic.
But some do. There's one book called "The Love Life of Our Children" or
(unintelligible).
In this book, the 18- to 20-year-old day care personnel...
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A man: Ok. Nobody's listening.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, see, I don't wanna dwell on this subject too much.
A man: I will just tell you how evil this state is.
Dr. Khalifa: Don't worry about it. It's the least of their problems. Do they worship God alone?
Dr. Khalifa: That's the least of their problems.
There's one thing I wanted to say. Oh, I wanna go back to what Elahi said.
Well, "like having 20 ice creams."
Because the child loves ice cream.
So, we say, give him something that he or she can identify with as something that is very good.
So, God is telling us Heaven is food and rivers of milk and honey and so on.
(unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Thank you. Because this is what I just told Eric. I said "I don't wanna dwell on this, on subject." A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You see, Eric, this is a good demonstration of when I... I remember, I told you "we are not politicians."
This is why as soon as you mention politics, the group loses interest. They didn't do it on purpose to you.
Dr. Khalifa: They're not being discourteous to you. Eric: I understand.
Dr. Khalifa: But it's just that we're not interested in politics. We're interested in what God wants us to do and politics don't mean a thing.
I always tell my friends "this is the least of their problems. Do they worship God alone?"
Eric: I just wanted to give an example of how Satan is trying to overcome this by forcing in it. A man: Al-Salaamu ‘Alaykum Ismail Barakat: Wa ‘Alaykum Al-Salaam Dr. Khalifa: Wa ‘Alaykum Al-Salaam
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. But it's all over the place, yes.
Eric: It hurts. I mean,... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, let's go to the next verse.
[30:27] And He is the One...
There's only one.
[30:27] ... who initiates the creation, ...
Dr. Khalifa: Remember Chester, in his speech, said "we cannot create the wing of a fly"?
Ismail Barakat: We won't create anything.
Dr. Khalifa: The wing of a fly, do you know how much weight that is? Do you know what it is made of?
Ismail Barakat: Gasoline.
Dr. Khalifa: If you look under the microscope, you can see those... It's built. It's designed.
And it moves at 10,000 movements per minute.
A woman: What?! Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Yes. A woman: Wow!
Dr. Khalifa: And it doesn't just move like this. I'm simplifying it.
Dr. Khalifa: There's a... Ismail Barakat: an angle.
Dr. Khalifa: There's a specific movement. They did it slow motion. And it's really...
Ismail Barakat: To make it fly. To make it fly, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: You can write a book on the movement of the fly's wing and how it is designed.
Now, what makes it? Think of a number 8 that the wing is drawing.
And you try to chase the fly with all your abilities.
You're trying to (unintelligible) and you sneak up on the fly. And you're going very slowly. And...
Dr. Khalifa: They have radars, see.
A woman: (unintelligible) when, in one Sura, you cannot catch a fly after it takes something from you. Even if you do, you cannot take it back.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: Does it mean that when it takes sugar, it disintegrates...?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, immediately, yes. A woman: Wow!
Dr. Khalifa: As a matter of fact, it's on the spot.
The mouth of the fly secretes enzymes that break up the sugar to its components, the glucose and fructose.
So, the fly is absorbing either glucose or fructose.
How are you gonna bind them back together?
Enzyme is a catalyst.
Any enzyme is a catalyst. It breaks up chemicals in an unusual manner.
It works on the chemical bonds between the two molecules, glucose and fructose.
I'll send you a bill for this chemistry lesson.
[30:27] ... He is the One who initiates the creation, then repeats it; this is the easiest thing for Him. ...
And "repeats it" can mean here in this world, where you see Elahe duplicated by Lillian. She's a repetition. There is Elahi all over again.
Or "repeats it" means in the Hereafter, also.
Dr. Khalifa: [30:27] ... this is the easiest thing for Him. ...
Ismail Barakat: "The easiest" means He's using a figure of speech.
Ismail Barakat: It means it is very, very, very easy for Him. It does not represent any... Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Ismail Barakat: But because, you see, the creation of the universe, Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala says, is more difficult than the creation of... Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Ismail Barakat: But since Allah creates Dr. Khalifa: I was gonna say it.
Ismail Barakat: by instructing, by saying Kun (كُن), Kun (كُن), a camel, or Kun (كُن), a fly, is the same. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Exactly.
Ismail Barakat: It's a figure of speech, I think.
Dr. Khalifa: I think this is the time to address that blasphemy in the Bible,
a human blasphemy, where it says "God created the heavens and the earth and then rested on the 7th... in 6 days and then rested on the 7th day."
We have the statement here in the Quran that says "we created the heavens and the earth and I was not tired at all."
It says "no tiresome touched Me." God says. This is in Sura 50.
See if we can find it.
Dr. Khalifa: It's very important to know this. God says it's the easiest thing for Him.
A woman: (2:255) لَا تَأْخُذُهُۥ
Ismail Barakat: (2:255) وَلَا يَـُٔودُهُۥ حِفْظُهُمَا Also, in Sura Al-Baqarah
Dr. Khalifa: No, this is running them. Ismail Barakat: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: But I was talking about the creation itself.
A woman: Even (unintelligible) A man: I know Fati. 50:38.
A woman: How about 2:...? How about, but I don't know. A man: 50:38. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: we're gonna look up page 5 2 0, 520, verse 38. Where's your (unintelligible)?
Oh.
It says,
[50:38] We have created the heavens and the earth, and everything between them in six days, and no fatigue touched us.
Ismail Barakat: So, He didn't need to rest on the 7th. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: This particular verse, which it happens to be 19 times 2, is a direct answer to the blasphemy of the writers of the Bible.
They confound the truth with falsehood.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes?
A woman: Page 42, Sura 2 (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
A kid: Mama.
Dr. Khalifa: This is what Ismail just quoted. But this has to do with running the universe.
The verse here that we're discussing that, "it's the easiest thing for Him, creation."
It's the easiest thing. So, directly related to it is 50:38.
And it is a direct answer to that Bible writers.
Ismail Barakat: (unintelligible)
Feroz: Days, when it says "days" like 4 days or 6 days, does it mean stages or periods or...?
Dr. Khalifa: Alright, Ok. Very good question.
Six days, although we'll go into another Sura, but the whole purpose of these Quranic studies is to understand. The six days is a yardstick.
Six days has nothing to do with days. It's a yardstick, a measurement.
Who's making the noise?
When you hear noises, please look and see if your child is making the noise. It's your responsibility to keep it quiet.
The six days is a yardstick. For example, we have this clock. It's a yardstick.
We look at it and we say "the plane will leave in one hour."
So, we know what one hour is.
It's a yardstick, 24 hours in the day.
So, God told us that God created the heavens and the earth in six days.
But we learn also that He created the earth in four days.
Even though the earth is a tiny, tiny mote. What does this tell us? There's a lot of information in this data.
What does this tell us?
If all these billions, trillions, decillions of heavenly bodies in their precise orbits
were all created in two days, and this tiny, tiny mote earth was created in four days.
What does this tell us? It tells us there is no life out there.
As confirmed by our journeys to the whole solar system. Probes went. We didn't see any creature on Neptune or the moon or Mars.
There's not a single tree out there.
But here, all the horses need Alfalfa and beans, barley.
So, every grain of barley had to be calculated, which horse is going to eat this.
So, this is why it took four days.
Dr. Khalifa: The six days, therefore, is a yardstick. It has nothing to do with days or years or whatever.
Ismail Barakat: Again, it's not a measure of time.
Ismail Barakat: Because, like I said, God says Dr. Khalifa: No. What I said.
Ismail Barakat: "Be" and it's a camel, and "Be" and it is a fly. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: It's the same thing. The process is the same.
Dr. Khalifa: I think a good demonstration is Moses' staff.
"Be a snake" and it was a snake on the spot.
Dr. Khalifa: Just like that. Do I know about "Be" and it is? Ismail Barakat: But...
Ismail Barakat: Yes, that's right. But,
But could it not be a measure of the importance Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala places on the test and on the human race?
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, it's really... It is also literal.
When God says He created the earth in four days and the whole universe in two additional days, it is literal, relative to each other.
Because there is a physical creation process, even if it is instantaneous.
Feroz: But I'm saying that it's more, it was more difficult to create the heavens. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: ...the sunrise in Tucson, every day until the end of the world, indicates the preciseness.
I mean, what is out there? There's nothing. There's space.
Anything can go in any orbit, but it is not. There is a line. Can you imagine a line
that the sun is moving in, and the earth is moving in, and the moon is moving in?
The whole thing is moving.
The earth around the sun and the moon around the earth.
Ok. The moon around the earth and they're both of them around the sun, and the sun around something
else in the galaxy, and the whole galaxy around something else.
Dr. Khalifa: It's very, very precise.
A man: Suddenly, it's a little cloud over a little house out in the desert.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly, and that was measured. Yes.
That rain fell on the dining hall where we were meeting.
Ismail Barakat: When we decided to change the schedule. BAM! Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: No, because Cecilia was there, and this frozen water came down.
Dr. Khalifa: It's all Cecilia's fault.
Confess.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Feroz: Rashad, yeah, dumb question, but do you think really that perhaps,
Feroz: like when the sun is going around, there's an angel really pushing it in accordance with what you are saying? Ismail Barakat: Yes, certainly.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Ismail Barakat: There are no angels pushing the sun. Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: See, what happened was we are living in the Big Bang right now.
We are living right now in the Big Bang.
Dr. Khalifa: Remember God says that the universe is expanding?
Ismail Barakat: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: There is movement.
Dr. Khalifa: Why is the earth hanging in space?
What is it that's holding it in space?
Ismail Barakat: The will of God. A man: Speed. Speed.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. It's like a bullet out of a gun.
Between... Let's say the bullet travels from here to that wall. Why is it hanging in space?
Ok. Let's stop everything. Ok. The bullet...
You shoot a bullet from here to here.
Dr. Khalifa: And as the bullet reaches this spot... Ismail Barakat: It freeze everything.
Dr. Khalifa: Freeze everything. Now, why is it hanging in space?
Because of the power of explosion.
Explosion from the gun. That's...
Ok. So, the Big Bang Theory, which is confirmed in the Quran, Sura 21, verse 30.
Yes. Keep Hani away from Lillian. Then, he'll go. Go sit with daddy.
The Big Bang Theory is confirmed in the Quran and confirmed by our own theories. The Big Bang is like this.
Ok. And there are pieces and shrapnels. Think of them as a bomb that exploded.
Dr. Khalifa: And we are sitting in one of the shrapnels. And it's traveling in space.
A man: And actually, we can hear the speed.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: if we...
Dr. Khalifa: So, God's creation is controlling this... It's not an uncontrolled explosion.
Dr. Khalifa: So, all these shrapnels are moving according to laws, physical laws that God already set in motion.
Ismail Barakat: Created. You know, if we can just expand this.
Dr. Khalifa: There's no angel holding the sun.
Ismail Barakat: If we can just expand this for a moment.
Ismail Barakat: Magnets, you have a North Pole and a South Pole. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: Ok. How does the North Pole know that this guy is the South Pole and he should be pushed away?
Rather than another North... Sorry, a North Pole that should be pushed away rather than a South Pole that should be attracted.
Ismail Barakat: How does a sodium atom Dr. Khalifa: It's a law.
Ismail Barakat: recognize that this is a hydroxide molecule and it should be attracted
rather than an iron atom that should be pushed away? How do they recognize...
Dr. Khalifa: Electromagnetic forces. Electromagnetic forces.
Dr. Khalifa: That we don't see. There are physical forces. For example, the sodium hydroxide, they click.
There's a certain thing that they click perfectly into each other to form the salt.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the physical thing. But there's also between them, there are electromagnetic forces that attract or repel, repulse.
Ismail Barakat: Yeah, but how do they know?
Dr. Khalifa: Who?
Ismail Barakat: The electromagnetic, the thing, the mechanism that pushes or attracts.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: How does it know that this is to be...
Dr. Khalifa: Well, God set the laws for these.
Ismail Barakat: So, it's not angels who are doing it? Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Not angels, no. That will be very difficult to explain.
To get an angel to have your exchange of food between your lungs and your blood and the oxygen.
You know, when they breathe, the oxygen goes in there to oxidize food.
It's coming in the blood to the lung.
The lungs are little balloons, very little balloons with a lot of vessels around them.
And they take the oxygen, get out the carbon dioxide.
Dr. Khalifa: There are billions of biochemical reactions going on. Do you want an angel for every reaction?
Ismail Barakat: Why not?
Dr. Khalifa: You'll have two billion angels inside your body.
Because of, the angel can hold the whole earth in one hand.
That's what the angels are.
An angel can hold the whole planet earth in one hand. One angel.
Dr. Khalifa: They're enormous creatures.
Ismail Barakat: But Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala (unintelligible) are guarding us. Dr. Khalifa: So are we.
Dr. Khalifa: Huh?
Ismail Barakat: How are there two of them guarding us?
Dr. Khalifa: They are. Because they have the capacity of being here at the same time. Yes. Ismail Barakat: To shrink?
Dr. Khalifa: Or not necessarily to shrink.
Dr. Khalifa: They may be encompassing the whole earth, but they're watching you over the earth.
Ismail Barakat: And when we say,
(23:97) رَّبِّ أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ هَمَزَٰتِ ٱلشَّيَـٰطِينِ (23:98) وَأَعُوذُ بِكَ رَبِّ أَن يَحْضُرُونِ
Dr. Khalifa: Then, comes the Shaytan to bother you out of here.
Ismail Barakat: So, an angel comes in to... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: to keep away the devils and his whisper.
Ismail Barakat: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, literally, the devil come and whispers to you, and will tell you, interfere in your understanding of the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: But when you seek refuge in God, there are angels assigned to come and to keep those...
Ismail Barakat: Whose job is to...
Dr. Khalifa: Because we're talking about the whole other dimension, invisible forces, invisible soldiers. The Quran always talks about them.
So, we're unaware of what is happening in the invisible direction.
Dr. Khalifa: Also, in the invisible dimension, there is no time, for example.
Ismail Barakat: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: And there is no distance.
So, when... how will the angels... You see, we think with our own dimension.
How will they travel 190 billion light years in one day, or in five minutes?
Because the distance is zero and the time is zero. So, they can travel in a second.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, I don't wanna go too deep into this.
Feroz: Can I ask one question?
Dr. Khalifa: A question?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Feroz: The reason I asked that seemingly dumb question, about an angel pushing...
The reason I'm saying it is because to us, physically, like, logically, scientifically, appears certain things.
Feroz: But the same way, you know, the clouds.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. The angels push the clouds.
Feroz: ...that the angels push them.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. The angels push the clouds, distribute provisions.
Dr. Khalifa: This has to do with us. This is the meaning of the angels falling prostrate before Adam, the human being.
Ismail Barakat: Quran, Allah says that the angels push the clouds?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, (51:1) وَٱلذَّٰرِيَـٰتِ ذَرْوًۭا
driving the winds, also.
And they use for or against people.
Dr. Khalifa: God says that with the thunder and the lightning, He hits whomever He...
Ismail Barakat: Yes, He sends the lightning. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
The angels have lots of functions here on the planet Earth, mainly associated with us.
Dr. Khalifa: They have to do with us.
Ismail Barakat: I thought actually, you know...
Dr. Khalifa: No, not the sun, though.
This is the big bang explosion. These are laws that rule that.
The angels will not go in there and connect the atoms and the molecules and separate them.
It's full of laws.
Dr. Khalifa: Electromagnetic laws between the atoms.
Feroz: Is it possible that the reason for the cause of the big bang, because the Quran says that,
you know, when they commit a blasphemy and say, like three, for example, the heavens are about to burst,
Feroz: could it be that this original mass heard something else, besides "La Elaha Ella Allah" and (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: Sure, why not?
Ismail Barakat: I don't, I didn't understand.
Dr. Khalifa: The blasphemy of Satan.
Dr. Khalifa: But this is a deliberate plan to give us the test.
Ismail Barakat: All of the... The purpose of all of this is to create the environment for the test.
Dr. Khalifa: Run the test, yes. The purpose of the whole, the seven universes.
(51:56) وَمَا خَلَقْتُ ٱلْجِنَّ وَٱلْإِنسَ إِلَّا لِيَعْبُدُونِ
Number 28.
[30:28] He cites for you herein an example from among yourselves: Do you ever elevate your servants or subordinates to the level where they rival you, and to the point that you pay them as much homage allegiance as is being paid to you? We thus explain the revelations for the people who understand.
Okay, to make you understand this, they say "Muhammad will intercede on the Day of Judgment."
So, let us put this in practice.
The Day of Judgment comes, and here is a man who is interceding on behalf of the believers.
Dr. Khalifa: So...
Ismail Barakat: Let Hagia explain.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, this is Ihsan's explanation.
So, Mr. Smith sees that Muhammad is interceding and putting the people in Heaven, according to their principles, right?
So, Mr. Smith goes to Muhammad and says "Please intercede on my behalf, I want to go to Heaven."
So, Muhammad says "Who are you?" He says "I'm Mr. Smith. I'm a good man."
So, the question is "how does Muhammad... ." We ask them "how will Muhammad know that Mr. Smith is a good man who deserves to go to Heaven?"
They say "well, God will tell him."
So, okay, okay.
So, Muhammad will say "God, is Mr. Smith good enough to go to Heaven?"
And God will say "yes, he's very good."
Dr. Khalifa: And Muhammad says "okay, put him in Heaven."
A woman: Oh, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Isn't this what intercession is?
I mean...
So, what did he do? I mean, what did Muhammad do?
So, what they did was, they made God Muhammad's secretary.
Subhan Allah. 'A'uzu Billah (أعوذ بِٱللَّه)
God be glorified.
Can you see the blasphemy?
They say... does Muhammad know all the people who are good and all the people who deserve to go to Heaven?
A woman: "Yes." Dr. Khalifa: "Yes."
Dr. Khalifa: Suppose I go to him, to Muhammad, and I say, "Please intercede on my behalf. I'm a good believer."
"I used to pray five times a day, and I believe the Quran alone. And I need to go to Heaven."
Will he know? Does he know me?
He'll say "who are you?" I'll say "I'm Rashad."
And he'd say...
So, according to them, he will ask God "Is Rashad, does he deserve to go to Heaven?"
God will say "yes." So, what is Muhammad doing then, if God already, since God already knows, what is, what is...?
You can see. So, they're setting up rivals with God.
This intercession business.
It's like God's intercession, also.
Hani, go sit with Daddy, honey.
This is the absurdity of idolatry.
This is why it is absurd.
And why it is blasphemous.
They don't think. They don't put it in practice, how will it happen.
And when the people get sick, and they write thanks notes to St. Jude.
This is setting up a rival with God.
Giving power to powerless creatures.
[30:29] Indeed, the transgressors have followed their own opinions, without knowledge. Thus, who can guide those who have been sent astray by GOD? No one can ever help them.
As you know by now, there's nothing you can do to make them understand.
Because God Himself has sent them astray.
God sent them astray. How can you guide them?
What are you trying to do?
"Look here, there's a great miracle. Can't you see it? What's wrong with you?!"
You know what's wrong with the person.
Muhammad gets very upset with those people.
Muhammad has the most logical approach to those people who do not follow the Quran alone.
He says "it tells you the Quran is fully detailed. So, why do you need anything else?"
"It tells you God bears witness, La Elaha Ella Allah, why do you have to add something else?"
But it's because God sent them astray.
Dr. Khalifa: They are prevented.
Ismail Barakat: But they made the choice first, though.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, of course.
Ismail Barakat: They decided to go astray, so God says "all right, if you're committed down this road, go." Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Again, it's their two key words. (4:115) نُوَلِّهِۦ مَا تَوَلَّىٰ
God turns everybody in the direction he chose.
In other words, there are several directions, right?
And we make the decision. This is the direction I want, and God will help us in this direction.
Like I said yesterday, the Pope probably saw very good signs that Mary is the mother of God.
Because God helps him in that direction. If he makes that strange statement, he will see signs.
Because you see him going around hypnotized and really, you know, believing Mary is the mother of God.
He's convinced. You know, he's holy.
Dr. Khalifa: Your holiness. Huh?
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Of course he does.
Yeah, this is one of the major doctrines, that Mary is the mother of God.
And I never forget it because that was the first question my mother-in-law asked me.
Dr. Khalifa: "god was an orphaned child." Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: "Do you believe in the mother of God?"
So, after I finished laughing, by the time I finished laughing, she didn't want me marrying her daughter.
Ismail Barakat: Rashad, can I ask one question relating to number 28?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, after Mabel, because she raised her hand first. Ismail Barakat: Ok.
Mabel: There was an Aya (verse) in the Old Testament, which is that God Almighty shows us, each of us, over and over again.
So, if we have, you know, a chance to make the choice, and then it says, and you continue, you reject
what I show you, you make that choice, then I force you into that choice.
Mabel: Is that the Aya (verse)?
Dr. Khalifa: This is it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. (4:115) نُوَلِّهِۦ مَا تَوَلَّىٰ
Nuwalihi (نُوَلِّهِ) means "we turn him."
Ma Tawalla (مَا تَوَلَّىٰ) means "the choice, the direction he chose."
Dr. Khalifa: Azuba, are you ready?
Ismail Barakat: Yeah, the direction he chose.
A woman: The whole issue is when Christians say that Jesus is the son of God.
I even have to think about saying it like that.
A woman: "Jesus is the son of God." Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A woman: The rationale that they give is that something must have gone on between God and Mary. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Yes.
A woman: And I think that it also has to do with the fact that we try to make God so human. We can't Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: conceive of Him as a human. Ismail Barakat: Yeah, they stripped Him of His divinity. They made Him human.
Ismail Barakat: In fact, speaking of this particular issue, Ahmed Deedat told us, he discussed this with somebody in South Africa.
Ismail Barakat: And he said, he actually said this. He said "God covered him."
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Ismail Barakat: Huh?
Dr. Khalifa: Who? The Christian? Ismail Barakat: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Ismail Barakat: The (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's so stupid, you know. If you think of it in terms of reproduction, it's like making love to a virus.
Would you like to make love to a virus?
I mean, it's not even that.
Dr. Khalifa: It is so, it's so bad. They do not value God. They have no... You can see the blasphemy.
Ismail Barakat: They stripped Him of His divinity. They made Him human.
In fact, they did exactly the opposite.
They say that He created man in His image.
The opposite exactly has happened.
Ismail Barakat: They created God in their image.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. With this picture in our mind, let's look at the end of Sura 19.
Because you'll understand why.
You'll understand why.
88. Page 311, verse 88. The Great Blasphemy.
[19:88] They said, "The Most Gracious has begotten a son!"
[19:89] You have uttered a gross blasphemy.
[19:90] The heavens are about to shatter therefrom, the earth is about to tear asunder, and the mountains are about to crumble.
Because they invented for the Most Gracious a son.
So, you can see the grossness of that blasphemy.
[19:90] ... the mountains are about to crumble.
[19:90] The heavens are about to shatter ...
Because such a stupid blasphemy.
A woman: Wow! Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: But I think the argument we can give back to them is when they talk about the Word.
You know, God, He spoke the Word. He said it, and something happened because He said it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: This is the same principle.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: He said it.
Dr. Khalifa: In the Quran. A woman: This is in their own words.
Dr. Khalifa: What do you want, when you encounter Christians?
I'll probably be repeating this for the next few weeks.
When you encounter Christians, ask them "where does it say in the Quran that Jesus is God... In the Bible that Jesus is God?"
Because there is no such thing.
They'll come up with these indirect statements.
"I am the way. I am the life. I am the truth."
Tell them "yes, he may be the way, he may be the life, he may be the truth. But it doesn't say I'm God. Where does it say?"
Dr. Khalifa: It's very easy to say "I am the way, I am the life, I am the truth, I'm God."
Ismail Barakat: You see... Dr. Khalifa: It's very easy, but he didn't.
Ismail Barakat: What I tell them, Rashad, is that Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala in the Quran, on every page, He stresses His Oneness.
That He is the Creator. He is the one God.
It is the principle that the Quran is all about, the Oneness of God.
Now, if Jesus is God, then obviously it must be very important.
Ismail Barakat: Show me once where he states that he's God. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Ismail Barakat: Otherwise, once. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Ismail Barakat: And in fact, nowhere does he, nowhere, does he say that he's God or the son of God or worship me.
Ismail Barakat: Nowhere does he say that.
Dr. Khalifa: Ihsan, remember that Catholic man who came to join us on the table at the future society meeting?
And he first, he said, he's a Catholic and he made the statement that Jesus was God.
I said "where does it say that in the Bible?"
Never.
Dr. Khalifa: Nowhere in the Bible does he say I'm...
Ismail Barakat: Most of them don't know, Rashad.
Dr. Khalifa: I know. Ismail Barakat: They don't know that it doesn't say that.
Dr. Khalifa: Especially Catholics.
Ismail Barakat: Because Catholics are not allowed to read the Bible.
Well, now they are, but until a short while ago, they were not allowed to read the Gospel, the Bible.
Dr. Khalifa: Even now they discourage that.
Ismail Barakat: Well, the Bible.
Ismail Barakat: But essentially, you see, to them, they relegate the whole Testament.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Cecilia is going to say something, but before she says something, what happened to the New York group? It was with...
A woman: The New York group? Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: They left.
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon? A woman: No, what? A part of them left, correct?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, no, I'm not... Farid was by herself.
But what happened to her group, Farid?
Dr. Khalifa: Cecilia's group, Nicole and...
A man: They left. Dr. Khalifa: ...Gary, how?
Cecilia: Gary is...
Dr. Khalifa: So, why is Cecilia here?
Cecilia: Oh, I don't, I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: You just walk in and see her sitting and...
Cecilia: Yeah. By God's Mercy, she's not here.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: They took the wrong part of the ticket off when she came. They (unintelligible) ticket off. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So they think.
Dr. Khalifa: She was crying. This is the first time she cried when leaving Masjid Tucson.
Dr. Khalifa: She was making two shorter trips, and she was crying.
A woman: I know. Dr. Khalifa: And God heard her.
Dr. Khalifa: Actually, they didn't take her wrong ticket in New York.
This was all done in retrospect.
Retroactive, it was a retroactive action.
Because when she cried here, I think some angels, God, we have to attribute the action to God, you know. God said "OK, keep her one more day. Be and it is"
Dr. Khalifa: So, they changed, they changed the ticket right in her pruse.
A woman: He extended her staying here.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, that's what really happened.
OK, Cecilia, what's the question?
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) a little bit sitting in St. Louis somewhere by now.
Cecilia: Yes, for a long time. Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead.
Cecilia: I just wanna go back to what we were reading about the Great Blasphemy. I think we sort of passed it over.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Cecilia: And verse 90, I think it's really important to see how Allah, the projection He gives to let us see how great a blasphemy it is.
Cecilia: That the heavens, you know, shattering. When we think in our minds about the heavens shattering and the mountains crumbling.
That you know, it's such an awesome, awful thing for the human being to deal with. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Cecilia: I mean, it's like almost destroying the earth. It's almost like destroying the planet in this particular situation.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Cecilia: And so it's important for us to, I feel, to sort of destroy this blasphemy
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Cecilia: at every point that we need it
Cecilia: because of the way that Allah tells us how bad it is.
Dr. Khalifa: Let's, let's look at the next page, Cecilia, page 312. This is the very next Sura.
It says, [20:1] T. H.*
[20:2] We did not reveal the Quran to you, to cause you any trouble. [20:3] Only to remind the reverent.
Now, we're gonna see the purpose of revealing the Quran. It is a great event.
[20:4] A revelation from the Creator of the earth and the high heavens. [20:5] The Most Gracious; He has assumed all authority.
[20:6] To Him belongs everything in the heavens, and the earth, and everything between them, and everything beneath the ground.
[20:7] Whether...
Oh, wait.
This is not the one. 18, was the Sura before.
It's with a simple mix-up.
Let's go to 18, the Sura before.
I thought it was the Sura right after.
That was beautiful, though.
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh
Cecilia: Give praises to God. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Alhamdu Lillah.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Sura 18, not 20.
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
[18:1] Praise GOD, who revealed to His servant this scripture, and made it flawless.
[18:2] A perfect (scripture) ...
Why?
[18:2] ...to warn of severe retribution from Him, and to deliver good news to the believers who lead a righteous life, that they have earned a beautiful recompense.
[18:3] Wherein they abide forever.
[18:4] And to warn those who said, "GOD has begotten a son!"
It is one of the main objectives of the Quran.
So, it is a major issue. It's a major, major issue.
And the destruction of one of Satan's biggest blasphemies by which he recruits his constituents.
Somehow we have that very interesting discussions that whenever we finished the page, we opened it.
Let's take a break.
Dr. Khalifa: Just general, general...
A man: I'll take these ladies to the airport.
Dr. Khalifa: What is the next flight?
A man: 3 o'clock.
A woman: 5 past 3.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, oh, 3 o'clock, this is the time. A woman: I think we can...
Parivash: Yes, this is the time.
Ismail Barakat: Well, Unless, unless you get to the airport. A woman: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: Two...
For those who didn't hear the story yet, two crazy people went to the counter this morning
at the airport and told, and told the employees at the counter "we'd like to fly to California."
And the airline people said "we're very sorry" with a sad face and a serious face,
"we're sorry this flight is cancelled today because it's Labor Day."
And these two crazy people cheered up and said "really?!"
The airline, the airline employees are used to fights.
They were ready to fight.
And because the people usually get upset.
And the people are apologizing.
"We're sorry the flight is cancelled."
And they're waiting for the reaction and to be defensive about it.
And then, they also saw this Japanese-looking girl utter two Arabic words "Alhamdu Lillah."
A man: "And I know. Obviously, something's wrong here."
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: Yes. Good one.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: Allahu Akbar. Allahu Akbar.
A woman: It's a strange look that I (unintelligible).
A woman: (unintelligible) in Tucson and we'd really like to stay here longer.
Dr. Khalifa: The airline people are still talking to themselves, you know.
Dr. Khalifa: This has 6 verses.
And we write 1 2 3 4 5 6.
So, this represents the last Sura of the Quran.
So, as you see, this is a very long number.
We're just making one number that includes every single verse in the whole Quran.
This long number consists of how many digits? Each one of these is called a digit.
This is a digit.
This is a digit. This is a digit.
So, the number of digits is 12,692
which is a multiple of 19.
The number of digits that include the number of every verse in the Quran preceded by the number of verses in every Sura.
Dr. Khalifa: And the long number itself is also a multiple of 19. Ismail Barakat: is divisible.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. This is the miracle that we have there on the wall.
So...
Ismail Barakat: That's twice
Dr. Khalifa: There are many, there are many other...
Ismail Barakat: ... 6346, right, Rashad?
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
Ismail Barakat: This number 12692 is exactly twice the number of Ayas in the Quran.
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Except we have the number of verses in every Sura.
Ismail Barakat: No, no, I'm saying that the 12692...
Dr. Khalifa: It is? A man: Divided by 2. A woman: Yes.
A man: 6346. Dr. Khalifa: Wow!
Ismail Barakat: That's exactly twice.
A man: Wow!
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. That's another, another piece of information.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Now,
this is the first Sura in the Quran. It consists of 7 verses. This is every verse in the Quran.
And the verse number 1 in Sura number 1 says, Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)
And then, we come here, we finish the last verse which is, ends with ...Wa Laddaalleen (1:7)
Then, we go to Sura number 2 which consists of 286 verses and then Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem doesn't have a number, does it?
Ismail Barakat: Well, put a zero there.
Dr. Khalifa: So, brother Ali Fazely suggested To Abdullah and myself, to some other people that you put a zero here
for the Bismillah. And every time we come across the Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem, we put a zero for it.
So, you can see that the number of digits increases. And we have a totally new number.
Dr. Khalifa: When you come to Sura number 9.
A man: No zero.
Dr. Khalifa: There's no Bismillah. So, you put the number of the Sura. You also include the number of the Sura.
So, you put the number of the Sura, it is surah number 1. You put the total number of verses. You put the number of every verse.
And when you find a Bismillah, you put a zero for it.
So, when you come to Sura 9, there's no Bismillah. So, you put the number of the Sura, which is 9, put the number of verses, which is 127,
without the two false statements. Then, instead of putting a zero... There's no Bismillah, right?
You know that, in Sura 9, you put 1, 2, 3, and so on to 127.
Then, you come to the next Sura, which is Sura number 10, put the number of verses in it which is 120, I believe.
Dr. Khalifa: 111.
A man: Well, first you put zero, huh?
Dr. Khalifa: 106?
Let's say 106. And then, Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem is zero. Then, the first verse, second verse, and so on to 106.
But Sura number 9, there's no count of zero because there's no Bismillah.
She's crying.
The new number Is 13,038 digits and it's also a multiple of 19.
If you put the zero here, there's no Bismillah, so if you put the zero here, the whole thing is destroyed.
Dr. Khalifa: It's not a multiple of 19 anymore. That's how sensitive it is. A man: Allahu Akbar
Dr. Khalifa: So, let's collectively fall prostrate before God facing the Qibla A woman: Allahu Akbar
Dr. Khalifa: and thank Him for this miracle.
A man: Allahu Akbar
A man: Subhan Allah
Dr. Khalifa: Allahu Akbar
Dr. Khalifa: So, we thank God for this tremendous gift.
A man: Wow! Dr. Khalifa: It is just...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, it's just...
A man: What is this 6346?
Dr. Khalifa: It's the total number of verses in the Quran including the Bismillahs.
Ismail Barakat: Lisa.
A man: The multiple of 19.
Ismail Barakat: It that Ok to be happy (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: He is happy. Huh?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: One thing you can ask...
A man: If you take chapter 9 alone, its number is divisible.
Dr. Khalifa: Say it again.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Allahu Akbar
A man: Chapter 9
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The minute (unintelligible). The world, you think the world tomorrow will be Muslims. All of them when they're Quranists tomorrow.
A woman: Allahu Akbar
Dr. Khalifa: But you know, God is giving a chance for the elite of the elite to discover it.
Dr. Khalifa: You think it's coincidence For you guys to be here at this time to witness this?
A woman: Allahu Akbar
Dr. Khalifa: It's not coincidence. This guy, for example, is not supposed to be here. It's against the law for him to be here.
A man: What law? What law?
Dr. Khalifa: That you know of. Yes.
A man: Ah, that's no law.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Feroz: Rashad, somebody, unspecified source, suggested
A man: We only say one... Feroz: that
Feroz: (unintelligible) that 12692 again itself is also prove that there are two false verses, right?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Feroz: And when you take 2 and 6346, it comes to that that 2 emphasizes the 2 false verses. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
Feroz: I told them.
Parivash: Feroz. Feroz.
Dr. Khalifa: When...
Parivash: Talking about the digits, which one you talk about? Dr. Khalifa: new (unintelligible) coming.
Dr. Khalifa: New information... Feroz: 12692
Parivash: ..692. Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: New information is too much. Feroz: It's 2 multiplied by 6346, right?
Feroz: This is the total number of verses in Quran. Parivash: Ok.
Feroz: It's 2 times, and the 2
A man: are the 2 false verses. Feroz: are the 2 false verses.
Feroz: So, that highlight is 2 times, you know. The 2 (unintelligible).
A man: Take out the 2.
Feroz: Because that 12,692 proves that the 2 verses are not in there. Parivash: Ok.
A man: You have... If you have the two verses in there, it's 6348. You take out two, you have 6346. Parivash: Yes. Exactly. Yes.
A man: Now put it under and see how many verses there are and you get 12,692.
Feroz: Batool just noticed that (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh
A woman: Subhan Allah
Dr. Khalifa: Great, Batool.
A woman: Allahu Akbar
Ismail Barakat: Behrouz, Behrouz...
Dr. Khalifa: It would, it would have been (unintelligible)
Ismail Barakat: Rashad, I suggest, I suggest that we nominate a committee to put the miracles in the database.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Feroz. Feroz: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: I suggest, I suggest that we nominate a committee consisting of maybe two people, yourself and Abdullah, and anybody else who is an expert in this field.
Dr. Khalifa: Lisa. Lisa. To (unintelligible) database.
Ismail Barakat: To create, yeah, to create a database for the miracles.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Because it's getting out of hand.
Ismail Barakat: It is out of hand. "Getting out of hand." Can you, can you tell me how many discoveries there are so far?
Dr. Khalifa: No, I don't know how. We're losing track.
It is utterly overwhelming.
Ismail Barakat: And the only way you can keep track of it is in the database that comes with it. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Feroz: Abdullah, you (unintelligible) the discoveries? Are they all written down somewhere (unintelligible)?
A man: No.
Abdullah: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: There are, Ismail, there are so many profound, profound miracles that I'm now (unintelligible) the conference or something, you know, because they became less
I am afraid to describe them as less important (unintelligible). But it's just, number 1, it's a matter of our own capacity to...
Ismail Barakat: To absorb it. Dr. Khalifa: To absorb it.
Ismail Barakat: No, but you see, Rashad. It's for posterity. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: We must create a database. Dr. Khalifa: I think we'll have to.
Dr. Khalifa: ...and being unable to give it to the whole world on national TV.
For example, CBS Evening News which out of fantasizing Douglas broadcasted. This is the CBS Evening News.
An overwhelming miracle is in the world, but it would have been frustrating if it were not for God's deliberate planning
which is actually a blessing for the special individuals who are to witness this miracle first.
God does this for a purpose, and also to give a chance to the people of the Lowest pit of Hell to oppose it and fight it
and make them aware of it. We have a certain mailing list including the top Islamist Muhammadans around the world.
Dr. Khalifa: And this information goes to them
Ismail Barakat: as it is discovered. Dr. Khalifa: as it is discovered.
A man: And it will disturb disbelievers. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And it will convince the Christians and the Jews. Dr. Khalifa: It has been disturbing them. First,
Dr. Khalifa: they were completely silent about it.
A man: And it strengthens our faith and enrage the disbelievers. Dr. Khalifa: They... whenever they meet annually for their budget,
Dr. Khalifa: There's a budget for (unintelligible). So, God is doing (unintelligible) will come. A man: And it will remove all traces of doubt from the hearts of the Christians,
A man: Jews, as well as the believers. Expose those who harbor doubt, and the disbelievers. Dr. Khalifa: And God will let the whole world know. Inevitable.
Dr. Khalifa: It's inevitable. Ismail Barakat: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ismail Barakat: The only thing is that I pray to God that that be in my lifetime.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, IN SHAA ALLAH. Ismail Barakat: Because I'd like to see it.
Dr. Khalifa: IN SHAA ALLAH, and this is (unintelligible) today or something. IN SHAA ALLAH, it will be in your lifetime.
Ismail Barakat: You never know.
A man: A warning.
Dr. Khalifa: It is, it is very soon.
A man: A warning to the human race. A warning to the human race.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Things are going very fast. I really think it's gonna happen, maybe, in the next couple of months.
Dr. Khalifa: And the trigger will be this translation.
Ismail Barakat: Is this information from yourself or from God?
Dr. Khalifa: That's... I think it's both because the sample that we've seen is the Salman Rushdie affair.
Here's a book that was sitting on the shelf collecting dust and all of a sudden it is headline in all newspapers, Radio, TV, for a month in every country of the world.
So, God is giving us a sample as what He can do to promote a book.
Dr. Khalifa: Now,... right. Right. Salman Rushdie... Ismail Barakat: Salman Rushdie (unintelligible)
A man: For those among who wish to... Dr. Khalifa: Now, there is something else
Dr. Khalifa: that happened in front of viewers, Ismail and Feroz, in Vancouver
where they tried to accuse me of tampering with the Quran. Do you remember?
They said "Rashad Khalifa just tampered with the Quran and he wrote the NuN, Noon Waw Noon."
Ismail Barakat: Yeah, but they stated that.
Dr. Khalifa: And the person who saved my neck at that time, ironically, was Sheikh Bin Baz's assistant, the second man in Saudi Arabia's Islamic (unintelligible).
He told him "no, there are many Qurans written like this."
Dr. Khalifa: And they were ready to kill me, right? Do you remember? Ismail Barakat: Yeah, yeah.
Ismail Barakat: This shut them up.
Dr. Khalifa: So, this translation, this translation is coming out without their 2 favorite verses.
I have to interrupt here and interject the fact that when I went to Egypt, and
but the only person who made it in Egypt was my nephew who will be a senior in college, next year.
Ismail Barakat: Sharif.
Dr. Khalifa: I took him with me to the Friday prayer and the only verses they recited in the Friday prayer were the two false statements.
Yes. Then, my brother Atif went to Egypt and of course, and I told Sharif, my nephew, to stick with Atif and give him all the information.
So, he did, went with him to the Friday prayer in another town, which happened to be my birth place and they recited the same two false statements.
A man: No!
Dr. Khalifa: These are, these are their favorite verses. They are totally in Satan's hand. These are Satan's verses. And they are absolutely... Where is Ahmed Rayan?
There is Ahmed Rayan. And I was praying behind him and his favorite statements were what,
when he came in front of me? These two false statements. This is the way we grew up.
Ismail Barakat: Rashad,...
Dr. Khalifa: Those were your favorite statements, right?
Ahmed Rayan: Yeah, at least (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
I prayed behind him and he read لَقَدْ جَآءَكُمْ رَسُولٌۭ مِّنْ أَنفُسِكُمْ
Ismail Barakat: Rashad Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: What did Mr. Ben Baz say about you? Ben Baz.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, what did he do?
A man: What is he thinking about you?
Dr. Khalifa: He thinks I should be killed as soon as possible.
A man: Ben Baz? A man: Ben Baz? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And then, he has to kill me first.
Dr. Khalifa: Sheikh Ben Baz is the supreme judge...
Ismail Barakat: Ben Baz is a lying son of a bitch.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, he's the supreme judge in Saudi Arabia and he has already issued the Fatwa that I should be killed as soon as possible.
A man: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, let, huh? Let me finish this idea.
Feroz: Will he make that stupid statement of offering a prize and give you more publicity?
A man: I wish...
Dr. Khalifa: But they will, yes. Of course, Saudi Arabia is much richer than Khomeini. So,...
Khomeini is in the middle of war. So, they will probably put a hundred million dollars on my head, just wait.
A man: Khomeini could have... Dr. Khalifa: This translation will come out without their two favorite verses.
Dr. Khalifa: As an authorizing translation. So, I'm expecting from the signs that God gave us from the Salman Rushdie affair,
and this coming out, I'm expecting something like that.
So, the answer to your question is "it is from God and from my own personal taking."
Dr. Khalifa: It's only a matter of time. There are a lot of knowledge.
A man: There is, there is perhaps only one difference which I'd like to submit to you for consideration.
People wanted to grab Salman Rushdie's book
Because it had pornography and whatever.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And tried to read it. Dr. Khalifa: No, I have no idea what's in it.
Dr. Khalifa: It could have been a bunch of boring nonsense but because of the publicity...
A man: It's boring nonsense. If you read it, you won't like... when you start to read it, you won't like it because it is not clear what language he's having.
A man: I have read it.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A man: I have good friends. And they're joking with me because I'm a Muslim.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And they bought this book "Satanic Verses." And they put it on the table just to offend me. Their house burnt down.
A man: Their house burnt down
Ismail Barakat: (unintelligible)
A man: And I (unintelligible)
A man: A childish...
A man: This man that made a program "The Africans." Who remembers his name? He came to Columbia University.
A man: A Chinese.
A man: He had full information about this Salman Rushdie. The Christians that gave him
about 800,000 (unintelligible) because he said he knows Salman Rushdie and his friend is, you know, he knows even from the
beginning when that book was published in India, what happened. And they asked him
"Why would you like to print this book (unintelligible) when you printed it so many things happened?"
A man: He said "he doesn't care." Animals' rule. I have to accept that, you know, because I was there.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, I have to remind you of the latest issue of the Perspective.
And the article that Edip wrote about Salman Rushdie because we cannot avoid the connection.
I mean, God teaches us with Article 19 Organization defending him.
The famous authors of this country defending him with a big sign behind him that says nothing but "19."
Salman Rushdie being born on the 19th of June.
The English name of Salman Rushdie, and Rashad Khalifa, the Arabic name, Salman Rushdie (سلمان رشدی), Rashad Khalifa (رشاد خلیفه) having the same number of letters.
All these are not coincidence. I mean, maybe 2 or 3 or 10 of them are coincidence,
but not all of these facts. What is Article 19 business? And June 19 (unintelligible)?
A man: Salman Rushdie? Dr. Khalifa: Yes A man: June 19th?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, the address, the address that you write to was about, I think, it was, huh? The first 1995. But that's not as important. But the address that they had to write to was also a multiple of 19.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Sorry. Would you feel therefore that your Quran translation will be selling like hot cakes like (unintelligible)? Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Right.
A man: IN SHAA ALLAH
A man: Lots of people will find out.
A man: ...bookshops, they have all different kind of Qurans.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: You ask "I want to buy books." And they ask me to go downstair and check all the books that I want.
And surprisingly, I found your translation, too.
It's dirty. The way they put it, I think they don't want nobody to buy it. And I pick it up and brought it up.
They said "why do you want to read this?" "I want to read it." He said "this man is crazy."
I laughed at them. Then, I put question before them. I said... Wait, wait. Yeah. I asked them, I asked them, why did he say he's crazy?
He said "because he said he's messenger or you're fine?"
"He said he's a messenger, but he didn't say he's Nabi (نبی)."
He said "yes, yes, yes, but..."
Then, I said "but what? Wait. First of all, you should read this Quran, this translation. Read it. Then, if you see something wrong, you condemn it."
He sit down "But maybe you're right."
A man: They don't read.
A man: They just follow what people say. Ismail Barakat: They don't read.
Ismail Barakat: I bet you Khomeini even doesn't read the...
A man: Then you know what, and he's selling it very expensive.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the necessity of America of what you just said, because the Quran prophesies that they will call you "crazy."
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They'll call you... Ahmed Deedat sent me a telegram that's all in English except for one word "Kazzab (Liar)."
God said they're gonna say that. So, everything is in English but the word that the Quran prophesied "Kazzab (Liar)."
A man: Going further in 74:38, it says that
[74:38] They are all prisoners of their sins.
And 39,
[74:39] Except for those on the right.
A man: [74:39] ... on the right.
Dr. Khalifa: Which verse are you talking about?
A man: 74:39
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, oh, 74:39.
Dr. Khalifa: (74:39) إِلَّآ أَصْحَـٰبَ ٱلْيَمِينِ
A man: [74:39] Except for those on the right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: What does it mean?
A man: receive their record in their right hand on the Day of Resurrection.
Dr. Khalifa: They are right. They are on the right. You're saying it. They are on the right.
A man: I don't understand what it means "being on the right."
Dr. Khalifa: Are they wrong? Are they wrong or right?
A man: "Being right."
Dr. Khalifa: Well, they're on the right. Are they right or wrong?
Ismail Barakat: They must be right.
A man: They are right but why did you choose to translate it "being..."
[74:39] Except for those on the right.
Dr. Khalifa: This is what the Arabic says. Ismail Barakat: This is what the Arabic says "on the right."
Dr. Khalifa: (74:39) إِلَّآ أَصْحَـٰبَ ٱلْيَمِينِ
A man: Yes, so it must have another meaning than "being.."
A man: "Except for those being right."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, but they happen to be right, also.
A man: Yes, but this...
Ismail Barakat: (74:39) أَصْحَـٰبَ ٱلْيَمِينِ in the Quran are always right.
A man: Yes, but this, this fact that they are right. We are not right. Because we are, we have made this, we are (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: We are what?
A man: Obviously, Chosen.
Dr. Khalfia: Ok. Because you're right.
A man: No, I didn't do it on my own. But it doesn't say so in Arabic.
Dr. Khalifa: Whatever, whatever it is, on your own, the fact is hopefully you are right.
A man: Yes, I hope so, but, but...
A man: Ashab Al-Yamin (أَصْحَـٰبَ ٱلْيَمِينِ), because on the Day of Judgement, Ashab Al-Yamin (أَصْحَـٰبَ ٱلْيَمِينِ) are the ones who are preserved by God for purity and Paradise.
And Ashab Al-Shemal (أَصْحَـٰبُ ٱلشِّمَالِ) are the ones who receive their record on their left hand, go to Hell. So, these are... That's right. That's right. So, these are on the right. They are the ones chosen.
Dr. Khalifa: Ashab Al-Yamin (أَصْحَـٰبَ ٱلْيَمِينِ) are continuously on the right and right.
A man: It says here [74:38] Every soul is trapped by its sins. Dr. Khalifa: Whatever the connection.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: [74:39] Except for those on the right.
A woman singing: I know you for so long Who knows your ins and outs.
He knows your whereabouts. He's watching you.
And He's watching me until Eternity, Eternity.
I know who's the One. Yes, I do.
And there is no doubt His love is all about. He's watching you. And He's watching me.
And He can set us free, set us free.
Who are we talking about?
It's the Creator. There is no one greater. He made everything...